Chaya Greisman

Software Engineer | Web Developer chayagreisman.com

| Greater New York Area | chayamgreisman@gmail.com LinkedIn || GitHub || Medium

About

Full Stack developer with experience in Rails and JavaScript, along with React, and frameworks for UI and design. With a business education and experience in operations strategy, I bring practical and creative solutions. Passionate about designing, building, and creating, my preferred art mediums are paper, pencils, wood, and code!

Skills

- Ruby Ruby on Rails
- SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite)
- JavaScript * React.js * Redux.js
- WordPress * Shopify * Drupal
- ◆ Bootstrap ◆ Semantic UI ◆ Flexbox
- Microsoft Office/G Suite Adobe
 CreativeCloud(working proficiency)

Education

Flatiron School

05/2020 - 08/2020 Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Excelsior College

2018 - 2021 BS Business

Santa Monica College

2016 - 2017

High School concurrent enrollment program, completed credits in Early Childhood Education

Projects

CUBICLE - GitHub | Video Demo

A project management dashboard app with intuitive design that allows users to more efficiently manage team members and tasks.

- ◆ SPA with a Rails backend (RESTful API) and JavaScript frontend.
- Implemented complex ActiveRecord associations and related CRUD actions for app functionality.
 Utilized Bootstrap for responsive design.

HOME-HUE - GitHub | Video Demo

A practical and fun interior design color inspiration + planning app.

Rails backend (RESTful API) and React frontend. Implemented React client-side routing. Leveraged external color detection APIs. Used Semantic UI framework for layout & design.

GELT- GitHub | Video Demo

A comprehensive personal finance management app for managing accounts and budgeting.

 Rails backend, React frontend.
 Implemented Redux for state management, React client-side routing, localStorage to store user information client-side.
 Used Bootstrap, Flexbox, and basic CSS for design.

Experience

Shine Corp Real Estate Management Operations Manager

Brooklyn, NY 09/2019 - 02/2020

- Designed and implemented a prioritization system for optimal tenant experience and property owner satisfaction, considerably reducing building violation numbers and improving communication flow.
- Coordinated with company field managers, tenants, private contractors and repairmen, as well as multiple government housing/building departments to maintain steady daily operations.

Executionists

Web Development Intern

Marina del Rey, CA 07/2019 - 08/2019

- Utilized UI prototyping tools to create wireframes and site hierarchy mapping for a complex web-project in its early development stages.
- Collaborated with team members and reported to company CTO in planning and implementing unique features including subsite admin permissions.

Gan West Preschool Teacher

Culver City, CA 06/2018 - 06/2019

Created and followed a curriculum in line with Early Childhood Education philosophies and psychology to promote a safe play-based learning environment for a Pre-K class of 15.